Finding Aid for the Miscellaneous Manuscripts Collection LSC.0100
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Author Identified
  - Everett Horace, 1780-1851. To H[ezekiah] Niles, Washington. 1831 February 16 and 1832 February 24 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Everett-Green, Evelyn, 1856-1932. Correspondence. 5 items. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Fairchild, Donald S. Correspondence to Donald S. Fairchild from various people. 1937-1938. 42 items. Holograph and typescript. (Box 25)
    Gift of Mr. Donald S. Fairchild.
    Letters to Fairchild when he worked for the Oxford University Press. Among the correspondents are Peggy Ashcroft, Sir Thomas Bazley, Perry Belmont, Robert Benchley, John Mason Brown, Norman Douglas, Harold Ede, William Fadiman, Lloyd Frankenberg, John Gielgud, Gerstle Mack, J. Herbert Hodgins, Sir Edward Marsh, Charles Mayo, Margaret O'Flaherty, Noel Sullivan, Benedict Thielen, Wanda (Willson) Witman, Emlyn William. Photostatic copies of many of the letters are in the folder following the original letters.
  - Fall, John. Farmington plan: contracts -- correspondence., 1948.; (Typescript, bound). (Box 198, Folder 7)
    Also, Farmington Plan newsletter no.1 and 2 with appendices.
  - Farnsworth, J. G. To Col. Horatio C. King, New York. 1882 December 9 1 p. Letter signed. (Box 16)
    Farnsworth informs King that Governor-elect Grover Cleveland has appointed them Adjutant General and Judge Advocate General respectively and arranges a meeting.
  - Farquhar, Francis. Correspondence with Dartmouth College faculty., 1939-1957.; (5 items, 5pp.). (Box 284, Folder 14)
    5 letters, some re Dartmouth Mountaineering Club journal issues for collection.
    Found in Dartmouth Mountaineering Club Journal.
  - Farquhar, Francis P[eloubet], 1887-1974. Correspondence. 1946 October 9 2 leaves. T.L.S. (Box 8)
    To Neal Harlow, San Francisco. Describing various editions of The Life of Joaquin Murieta. With the above: Positive photostats of the first two pages of the 1859 and 1861 editions published by Butler & Co., San Francisco.
  - Farr (?), William. Als to Eben Pool, Jr. NYC. Ca. 1874 Aug 26 (Box 5)
  - Fast, Howard. Letters, postcards, slides and photograph [autographed to]., 1969.; (13 items, 7pp.). (Box 289, Folder 5)
    3 letters and 7 postcards, many re divining. Slides related to 7 July 1969 letter.
  - Fendall, P[hilip] R[icard], 1794-1868. To [John Charles] FrTmont, Washington. 1852 February 28 5 pages. L.S. (Box 8)
    Purchased of Hamilton, 1953 November 19. Also on negative microfilm #03189, John Charles FrTmont papers, 1846-1861.
    Letter concerning land in California.
  - Fenn, George Manville, 1831-1909. Signed correspondence. V.p. ca. 1870-1909 28 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
    16 letters, 1890-1905, are addressed to Fred A. Turner.
  - Ferdinand II, Emperor of Germany, 1578-1637. Letter to Louis XIII, King of France. Ratisbonne. 1623 March 28 3 p. 33 x 21 cm. Manuscript with holograph signature. (Box 30)
    This letter is written in Latin.
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1919-. D. H. Lawrence revisited. Taos, New Mexico. 1962 3 leaves. 21.5 cm. Holograph. (Box 17)
    First draft of this poem, written 1962 May 1. Not known if published. With this is a typescript copy of the manuscript and an account (1 leaf, typescript) by an unknown person of the writing of the poem. In a gray-green paper case.
  - Ferlinghetti, Lawrence, 1919-. Meditation on observation-affliction (written on the back of a map of Harvard College). Cambridge, Massachusetts. 1868 April 17 1 l. 43 x 35 cm. Holograph. (Box 23)
    Oversize. A poem of 211 lines arranged in four columns. Unpublished as of October 1968.
  - Ferrier, James Frederick, 1808-1864. Correspondence. 1852 May 22 1 item. Holograph. (Box 19)
    1 letter to Thomas De Quincey.
  - Ferris, Cha[rle]s G[oadsby] 1796-1848. To [Martin Van Buren] the President of the United States and William L[earned] Marcy, New York. 1838 Janurary 23 and 1839 December 6 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Field, Mrs. Isobel (Osbourne) Strong. Autograph. 1 folder. (Box 25)
    Taken from PS659 S75S Spinners' Book of Fiction.
  - Finley, S.H. Report of the Metropolitan Water District of Southern California on the San Jacinto tunnel strike., 1937. (Box 190, Folder 6)
  - Firbank, Arthur Annesley Ronald, 1886-1926. Correspondence. 1916-1917 4 items. (Box 6)
    Purchase I. K. Fletcher.
    4 letters to Grant Richards, referring to advertising Firbank's writings and his accounts.
  - Fish, Hamilton, 1808-1893. Correspondence. 1865-1890 3 letters. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Letter to Senator W.B. Allison of Iowa, December 13th, inviting him to dinner. Letter to Joel Munsell, New York, 1865 December 11, ordering a copy of Halls['] Eastern Vermont. Letter to General James Grant Wilson, New York, 1890 January 23, acknowledging receipt of copy of Wilson's address before Onieda Historical Society.
  - Fish, Hamilton, 1849-1936. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Teachers' Certificate. 1819
    A recommendation for Mr. Samuel Mills from Jabez Pond Fisher.
  - Fisher, M.F.K. (Mary Frances Kennedy), 1908-. Archive. (Box 170)
    [Includes]: correspondence with William Targ, some typescript chapters for With Bold Knife and Fork.
  - Fitch, Ashbel Parmelee, 1848-1904. Correspondence and scrapbook. 1870-1888 2 v. (Box 32)
    One volume of letters received by Fitch, 1888 May-July, while serving in the 50th Congress as a Republican representative from the 13th New York District and concerning his speech, 1888 May 16, delivered in the House of Representatives on tariff reform and in defense of the Mills Bill. Some letters are requests for printed copies of his speech. A letter, 1888 May 18, from Henry George is included. There is also a scrapbook, 1870-1882, containing clippings and broadsides pertaining to his law practice in New York City.
  - Fitzgerald, Francis Scott Key, 1896-1940. Letters, signed, to Cameron Rogers. V.p., v.d. 1934 Jan 24 and 1934 Apr 15 2 items. Typescript. (Box 5)
  - Fitzgerald, Percy Hetherington, 1834-1925. Signed correspondence. V.p., v.d. ca. 1902-1903 43 items. Holograph. (Box 6)
    Many of these letters are about Charles Dickens. 4 letters to Frederick George Kitton, regarding Charles Dickens and the Dickens Fellowship, 1902-1903. 1 letter to Andrew White Tuer, undated.
  - Flagg, A[zariah] C[utting], 1790-1873. Letters to various persons. 1831-1841 3 pieces holograph signed. (Box 9)
    Flagg writes to Secretary of the Navy Woodbury, concerning an appointment, endorsed by Woodbury, to Luther Bradish, concerning a pamphlet, and letter concerning New York State prisons. Letter to Woodbury signed by Silas Wright.
  - Fonblanque, Albany William, 1793-1872. Correspondence. 5 items. Holograph.
  - Foote, Mary (Hallock), 1847-1938. Correpondence to Herman Whitaker, Grass Valley, California. October 17 1 folder. (Box 25)
    Taken from Collection PS659 S75S Spinners' Book of Fiction.
  - Ford, J. K. To W. J. Alxius, N.Y. 1852 March 6 Holograph signed. (Box 4)
  - Ford, Roger, comp. A catalogue of the various editions [of The Compleat Angler, by Isaak Walton and Charles Cotton] in the library of Roger Ford, Esq. np, nd. 25 leaves, typescript with holograph notes, bound. (Box 10)
    Purchase: Wreden, 1954 February 1.
    Clippings from dealers' catalogs are also included.
  - Forsyth, L. N. Letters to L.C. Powell. Booklets re: "Art & Aviation". In a brown paper envelope. (Box 4)
  - Foster, John Watson, 1836-1917. To James Wadsworth, Washington. 1883 February 19 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 16)
    Concerning diplomatic communications with the Mexican minister and the delay in negotiations. Foster was newly appointed minister to Spain.
  - Fox, Gustavus Vasa, 1822-1883. To Gen. John S. Tyler, Washington. 1865 September 16 2 p. Letter signed. (Box 16)
    Fox, Assistant Secretary of the Navy, describes a new accounting plan to be used at naval stations and asks Tyler to serve with others to examine the efficacy of the plan.
  - France, Anatole. Letter to Professor W.E. Clark (University of Chicago)., 1912. (Box 194, Folder 4)
    Also, two magazine pictures of unknown man.
  - Franklin, Benjamin, 1706-1790. Correspondence to Sir Edward Newenham, Philadelphia. 1785 October 3, 1787 May 24, and undated. 3 letters (negative photostat). (Box 33)
  - Fraser, James Baillie, 1783-1856. Letters, signed, to various persons. V.p., v.d. ca. 1827 4 items. Holograph.
    1 letter dated 1827 June 3 to Mr. Carpenter regarding John Burnet, the artist.
  - Freud, Ralph and Ida. Christmas card., 1966.; (Handmade). (Box 191, Folder 5)
    Gift of Page Ackerman.
  - Freeman, Edward Augustus, 1823-1892. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Frey, Enas. Letter to "Mr. Edward Saiter, and Wife.", 1864. (Box 194, Folder 7)
    Posted Marion, Ohio, dated June 3, 1864, re wife's death, children's military service, the war.
  - Frey, Leander. Letter to Mr. Saiter., 1862. (Box 194, Folder 6)
    Posted from Covington, Kentucky, dated "12th 62," camp of Co. E, 96th Regt. Ohio Vols.
  - Frothingham, Nathaniel Langdon, 1793-1870. Correspondence to Ralph Waldo Emerson. 1861 April 6 1 piece. (Box 29)
  - Froude, J.A. Letter to James F. Gluch, Esq., no year, 22 June.; (1 item, 1p.). (Box 282, Folder 10)
    re one of Froud's Manuscripts. Penciled at top: Archbishop of Canterbury.
  - Frye, Burton. The Decker press of Prairie City, Illinois, 1950. 17 p. Mimeograph. (Box 15)
    A history of the James A. Decker Press, which specialized in publication of poetry.
  - Furniss, Harry, 1845-1925. Self-portrait (rear view), signed. London. 1900 February 1 p. Ink sketch, holograph. 17.5 x 11.5 cm. (Box 27)
    Removed from: Nunn, John J. Mrs. Montague Jones' dinner party... [Illustrations by Harry Furniss]. London, 1872.
  - Furst, Henry. [Correspondence to Andy Rolle and 5 p. typescript Ms]. (Box 7)
    Gift: Andy Rolle, May 1952.
    5 TLS's. 1 Ms, 5 p.
  - Gallagher, John. "Personal reminicences of the war in upper and lower California between American and native troops.", (Typescript). (Box 190, Folder 5)
    Gift of David Clark.
  - Gallup, Albert, 1796-1851. Letters sent, Albany. 1843 April 29 - 1846 October 30 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Letters sent as Collector of Customs for the Port of Albany to the following, who held the office of Collector of Customs for the District and Port of New York: Edward Curtis, C.P. Van Ness and Cornelius Van Wyck Lawrence.
  - Garland, William. Letter to Sam Glane., 1932. (Box 192, Folder 15)
    re participation on a committee of the 10th Olympiad (1932: Los Angeles).
  - Gaspar Manor, Somersetshire, Great Britain. Bailiff's accounts. 1764-1799 84 pieces in one folder. (Box 31)
    LCP purchase: Peter Murray Hill.
    Bailiff's accounts of the manor of Gaspar from Lady Day, 1764-1799. Accounts are addressed to Colonel Sir Isaac Rebow, owner from circa 1764 to 1782. After 1782 they are addressed to Mrs. Mary Rebow and the executors of the estate. Martin Shepherd was bailiff from 1764 until 1783. His son Charles became bailiff between 1783 and 1799, but the year is uncertain as records for this period are wanting. The accounts include a valuation of the estate made in 1772 by George Sangslor, as directed by Thomas South, then steward of the estate. This gives annual realization from farm rentals and cutting of timber as 280. Receipts for payment for work done on the estate by the Shepherd family and other tenents indicate repairs made, wood cut, et cetera. Receipts for 1799 bear a two- pence stamp. Land tax, poor rates, and church rates are also noted.
  - Gates, William, 1788-1868. To Nathan P. Ames, Fort Moultrie, South Carolina. 1834 May 23 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Gates, major of artillery, orders new pattern swords from the Springfield, Massachusetts armory.
  - George I, King of Great Britain, 1660-1727. Letter to the Court Official Spirman at Cologne. Hanover. 1705 February 14 3 p. 30 x 20 cm. Manuscript with holograph signature. (Box 30)
    This letter, written while George was Elector of Hanover, instructs Spirman how to vote at the Congress for Dirpholtz and Spiegelberg. With typescript translation.
  - Gernett, Richard, 1835-1906. Correspondence. 1882 May 20 1 folder. (Box 25)
    Taken from: Richard Garnett. Iphigenia in Delphi...London, 1890, T. Fisher Unwin.
    Holograph letter to Mr. Conway about some Emerson works in the British Museum.
  - Gershwin, George, 1898-1937. Mischa Yascha Toscha Sascha. 1930 July 2 leaves. 33 x 26.5 cm. Holograph. (Box 23)
    Gift of Muriel Donaldson, 1960 June.
    Oversize. A piece of music. "To Will Donaldson my old friend with every good wish. George Gershwin."
  - Gilberg, Ange. 1 als to Dr. Jean Hershold. 1945 (Box 5)
  - Gillet R[ansom] H[ooker] 1800-1876. Letters to various persons. 1834-1876 13 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
    Letters written between 1846 and 1849 written as Solicitor and Register of the Treasury.
  - Glascock, William Nugent, 1787-1847. Correspondence. 2 items. Holograph. (Box 29)
  - Glendinning, Robert M. (Box 199, Folder 7-9)
    - Book reviews., 1946. (Box 199, Folder 7)
      Chepil, W.S. Dynamics of wind erosion (2 copies).
      Hanna, Phil Townsend. Dictionary of California land names (1946).
    - Correspondence., 1941. (Box 199, Folder 8)
    - "Desert change: a study of the Boulder Dam area.", n.d. (Box 199, Folder 9)
      Two drafts, one with appended illustrations, for Scientific monthly magazine.
  - Goldsborough, Rob[ert] H[enry] 1779-1836. Letters to various persons. Circa 1835 2 letters. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Goodrich, Nathaniel. Letter to Francis Farquhar., 1953. (Box 194, Folder 1)
    Found in Goodrich's Waterville Valley (1952).
  - Gordon, Edgar B. "Bulletin on Community Music and Drama." 1915 April. (Box 16, Folder 68)
  - Gorgas, Josiah, 1818-1883. Correspondence. 1861 May - October 3 pieces, signed. (Box 31)
  - Gorgas, Major and Chief of Ordinance of the War Department, Confederate States government, writes to an officer and to the governors of Virginia and North Carolina on the subject of guns, armories and ammunition needed by the government. (Box 31)
  - Gourmont, Remy de, 1858-1915. Epilogues: L'Alcool et Torquemada. 1899 8 leaves. 22.5 centimeters. Holograph. (Box 12)
    An essay published in Mercure de France, Paris, May, 1899. Also published in "Epilogues: deuxiFme sTrie, 1899-1901," Paris, 1921, Volume II, page 44.
  - Graham, Elanor N. Title deed to 2 lots in San Ysidro., 1912. (Box 198, Folder 5)
  - Mrs. Gregson. Mrs. Gregson's memoirs., n.d.; (Typescript copy). (Box 199, Folder 2)
    re life in California to 1851.
  - Graham-Little, Sir Ernest Gordon. Letter. 1 folder. (Box 11)
  - Grimke, Dr. John. Letter from G.R.A. Brown., 1817 29 July.; (1 item, 4pp. [holograph]). (Box 282, Folder 15)
    re repayment of loan.
  - Grattan, Thomas Colley, 1792-1864. Correspondence. Circa 1826 10 items. Holograph. (Box 17)
    1 letter to John Poole, 1826 June 26.
  - Greenaway, Kate, 1846-1901. Drawings from "Marigold garden". Circa 1885 2 items. 28.5 x 19.5 cm. Original pencil sketches. (Box 30)
    "From market" appears on page 18. "In an apple tree" appears on page 23. "Marigold garden; pictures and rhymes by Kate Greenaway" was first published by George Routledge and Sons. London, 1885.
  - Grimm, Wilhelm Karl, 1786-1859. Correspondence. 1813 April 1 1 item. Holograph. (Box 17)
    1 letter to Mohr & Zimmer, Booksellers. Haydon, Benjamin Robert, 1786-1846. Correspondence to Lord John Russell. 1831 November 18 1 item. Holograph.
  - Grundy, Felix, 1777-1840. To Samuel Carrwell, Washington, D. C. 1814 March 7 1 p. Holograph signed. (Box 31)
    Grundy, Representative from Tennessee, asks Carrwell to deliver a check to certain persons in that state.
  - Guinn, Mabel Elizabeth. Collection of Los Angeles High School programs, dance programs, valentines, and ephemera. 1886-1902 47 pieces in 1 folder. (Box 30)
    Purchase: Dawson's.
  - Gutzkow, Karl Ferdinand, 1811-1878. Uriel Acosta. A tragedy by Karl Gutzkow, translated from the German by Alfred Baskerville. Circa 1840 42 pages holograph. (Box 13)
    From the Spinoza collection of Dr. A. Wolf.
  - Gwin, W[illiam] M[cKendree] 1805-1903. To A. A. Kincannon, Ripley [Miss.] [18]45 August 6 1 l. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Hackman, [?]. Inteview., 1977 11 October.; (3 items: On reel-to-reel [1] and cassette [2]). (Box 286, Folder 9)
    Notation: "NHPRC - Cal State Archives, Sac."
  - Hager, H.C. (Box 188, Folder 5-7)
    - Diary., July 4-September 22, 1896. (Box 188, Folder 5)
      Book 1 of 3.
    - Diary., August 14-October 19, 1897. (Box 188, Folder 6)
      Book 2 of 3.
    - Diary., December 27, 1888-December 23, 1889. (Box 188, Folder 7)
      Visits to China and St. John's Island.
      Book 3 of 3.
  - Haggard, H. Rider. Manuscript., 1908(?).; (1 item, 5pp. [holograph, signed]). (Box 285, Folder 12)
    Outline for plot and persona for The Yellow God (1908).
  - Halstead, M[urat] 1829-1908. To A. S. Smyster [?], Cincinnati. 1887 October 12 1 l. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Hammarstrand, M. W. To C. W. M. Smith, Indian Gulch, California. 1867 July 5 2 p. ALS (Box 7)
    Purchased from Zamboni, 1952 April.
    Letter concerning the assay of an ore sample sent from his claim at Indian Gulch, Mariposa County, California.
  - Hamilton, Alexander West. Correspondence and accounts. 1808-1820. 59 pieces in two folders. (Box 31)
    Mathews purchase: London cat. series, Item number 124: 209. 1951 December.
    45 holograph letters signed to Alexander West Hamilton of the Pemberton Valley Estate, St. Mary's, Jamaica [customs agent, Kingston, Jamaica, 1811-1820?] concerning consignments of cargo in the ships "Robert," "Middlesex," and other. Letters are from Robert Jamieson, captain of the "Robert," and from various plantation owners. Also includes 14 documents enumerating amounts and types of cargo, by whom sent, disposal, and prices obtained. West appears to have represented a Glascow merchant's investment firm [West India Merchant's] connected with one James Ewing.
  - Hammond, Jabez D[elno] 1778-1855. To William M. Morrison, Cherry Valley [N.Y.]. 1842 October 16 1 l. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Hamnett, Nina, 1890-1956. Correspondence. 1914-1951 36 items. Manuscript. (Box 19)
    17 letters from Jocelyn Brooke, 1946-1951. 1 letter from Henri Gaudier-Brzeska, 1914 July 13. 10 letters from Duncan Grant, 1945-1948. 2 letters from Leonard Merrick, 1923 and 1932. 1 letters from Osbert Sitwell, 1931 April 19.
  - Hanson, A.E. Interview by James Mink., 1977 20 April.; (2 cassettes). (Box 286, Folder 10)
  - Harrell, Orville, J. Flowing valley. 1953 282 p. Typescript. (Box 11)
    Carbon typescript with holograph corrections. Published by Mcbride, 1953.
  - Harris, Frank, 1855-1931. Letter, signed, to Christopher Millard. New York. 1919 Sept 27. 1 p. Typescript. (Box 4)
    Ex libris: C. K. Ogden
    Harris discusses Aleister Crowley, among other things.
  - 1923-1925 Harris, Frank, 1855-1931. Moore versus Harris. An intimate correspondence between George Moore and Frank Harrisalso a remarkable character sketch of Harris by G. Bernard Shaw. Chicago, Privately Printed [by Guido Bruno] 20, [2] p/ 5 illus. 15-1/2 cm. (Box 4)
    Purchase: I. Poole, June 1951.
    "One thousand copies of this book have been printed and the type distributed. This is No. 824." Bound in wrappers. Laid in: 1. Letter, signed, from Frank Harris to John H. Hogan. Nice, July 23, 1923. 1 p., holograph. 2. Letter, signed, from Arthur F. Bird to John H. Hogan. London, March 17, 1924. 1 p., typescript.
  - Harlan, Jacob W. 1 manuscript bill of sale signed by Harlan. 1852 March 20 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Harlan. California '46 to '88. F864 H22c
  - Harland, Henry, 1861-1905. Correspondence, signed, to various persons. Circa 1880-1905 3 items. (Box 29)
  - Harrison, Mary St. Leger (Kingsley), 1852-1931. The Wreck of the Golden Galleon - Manuscript., n.d.; (1 item, 77pp. [holograph]). (Box 282, Folder 7)
    Purchase.
  - Harvard University. To the Corporation of Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts. 1834 April 16 5 l. manuscript (letterpress copy). In black paper portfolio with flaps. (Box 12)
    Proposition for increasing student enrollment by scholarships, concluding: "All which is submitted respectfully by Harvard University..."
  - Hauser, Benjamin Gayelord (Box 286, Folder 1-2)
    - Dictionary of Foods [Manuscript], book review (1969)., 1939-1969.; (5 items, 126pp., typescript carbon, signed). (Box 286, Folder 1)
      Also includes one issue of Hauser newsletter (1969), Christmas card, and health food pamphlet.
      Gift of Dorohy Blankfort.
    - Dictionary of Foods., (1 item - binder). (Box 286, Folder 2)
      Gift of Dorothy Blankfort.
      For manuscript text SEE: this Box, folder 1.
  - Havenmayer, William F. Correspondence. 1 folder. (Box 25)
  - Havison, Richard. To Thomas Barclay, N.Y. 1802 April 7 Holograph signed. 2 p. (Box 4)
  - Hawkes, Francis S. 1 als. 1858 July 21 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Duyckinck, E. A., A memorial of Francis S. Hawkes. Z881 N44m
  - Hayward, Joel A. Memoirs., 1862-1863.; (Typescript). (Box 198, Folder 6)
    Reminiscences of military service during Civil War.
  - Hazard, Ebenezer, 1744-1817. To Messrs. Wharton and Lewis,Philadelphia. 1797 Sept 29 Holograph signed. (Box 4)
    Concerning insurance on a ship sailing to Jamaica, B.I.
  - Hazlitt, William, 1811-1893. Correspondence. 1835, 1851 5 p. (Box 5)
    Letter to J. Macrone. N.p., 1835. 2 p. Letter to Messrs. Fullarten. London, 1851. 3 p.
  - Heath, James P., 1777-1854. To H[ezekiah] Niles, Washington. [18]33 December 10 1 l. A.N.S. (Box 9)
  - Hedrick, Earle Raymond and Helen Breeden. Ancestors and descendants of Dr. Earle Raymond Hedrick and Helen Breeden Hedrick., 1977. (Box 192, Folder 16)
    Geneology of Clyde Lewis Hedrick.
    Gift of C.L. Hedrick.
  - Hendricks, Thomas Andres, 1819-1885. Correspondence. 1867 May 1 piece. Holograph signed. Envelope. (Box 16)
    Letter from [Colonel] James Gavin [?] to Hendricks, Greensburg, Indiana, 1867 May 4, concerning appointment for West Point. Letter from Hendricks to same written on verso of leaf, Indianapolis, 1867 May 8, replying that the district vacancy is already filled and that the matter is out of his hands.
  - Henley, William Ernest, 1849-1903. Correspondence. 1 item. Holograph. (Box 12)
  - Henri II. Expenditures., 1559.; (1 vellum leaf). (Box 193, Folder 2)
    Recording expenditures for May 28, 1559.
  - Henry, Eliza. To Harmanus Bleeker, New York. 1843 October 9 2 pages. A.L.S. (Box 9)
  - Henry, Guy Vernor, 1839-1899. To Mrs. Childs, Fort Myer, Virginia. 1892 November 2 2 pp. Holograph signed.
    Henry, military officer, writes a complimentary letter to the wife of a friend.
  - Hersholt, Jean. Letter to Ralph Freud., 1953 March 23. (Box 188, Folder 4)
  - Hickey, W. To [Henry] Clay [Washington]. 1841 March 29 1 l. A.L.S. and 9 pages extracts. (Box 9)
    Covering letter transmitting "extracts and references shewing the sentiments of General Jackson, while President, respecting the tariff."
  - Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1823-1911. Correspondence to Charles Eliot Norton. 1890 March 26 1 item. Holograph. (Box 19)
  - Higson, John. Correspondence. ca. 1869 (Box 5)
    Removed from: Higson, John. Historical and descriptive notices. English local.
    1 als 1869 Nov 23. 1 clipping signed "H"
  - Hodges, George, bp., 1856-1919. Correspondence. 1896-1900 11 letters. Holograph and typescript signed. (Box 18)
    Letters from various Protestant Episcopal Bishops, including John H. Vincent, Henry M. Jackson, David S. Tuttle, William Part, Cleland K. Nelson, Joseph H. Johnson, Thomas A. Starkey, John Scarborough, Chancey B. Brewster, and Sidney C. Partridge. Some of the letters concern the Christian Social Union, and there is one letter from Bishop Hodges to a Mrs. Gozzaldi, enclosing an autograph of Sidney C. Partridge, Bishop of Tokyo.